Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and
today we're talking about
eating food and certain
foods that people don't eat.
That's right so today we
have special diets, we're
going to talk all about
being a vegetarian or a vegan
and we're going to explain all
these words when we come back.
So now let's just
listen to the dialogue.
Sure, what do you
feel like having?
I really feel like having a
big juicy steak. Oh, okay.
I don't eat meat but that's
fine. I'm sure wherever
we're going they will
have other options right?
I didn't know you were
a vegetarian. I'm not.
I'm a vegan. Oh what? A
vegan. I don't eat or use
any animal-based
products. I don't wear leather,
eat eggs, drink milk, or anything
that comes from an animal.
I used to be a
pescatarian before which
basically means you
don't eat meat but still have
fish and seafood.
Wow that's interesting.
It must be tough. It's a bit
difficult to find vegetarian
friendly restaurants
sometimes but since more and
more people are vegetarians or vegans
nowadays, it's getting a bit less difficult.
All right we're back so
now probably a lot of you
have an idea of what it
means to be a vegetarian
but let's take a look at that word
and many more on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So a
vegetarian is a noun. I'm a vegetarian.
Vegetarian is a noun. It's a
person you say I am a vegetarian.
He is a vegetarian
and in this case
a vegetarian and vegetarian
person does not eat
meat so no chicken no
beef none of that stuff.
That's right so as you
as you can see it has the
prefix "veget" like
"vegetable" so that's what they
they just eat
vegetables and it's a little
bit hard to say what
vegans don't all, sorry.
It's a little bit hard to
say what all vegetarians
do or don't eat because
some people have
different rules. That's
right some people eat
eggs some people don't
but there is something that
is a little bit different
from a vegetarian it's
called a vegan and this person has many
many rules about what he can or cannot eat.
Right so if vegetarian basically
does not eat meat a vegan as we
saw in our dialogue
doesn't wear leather for
example doesn't wear
leather shoes or a jacket
or use or eat anything
that comes from an animal.
That's right so no eggs
right no no foods that
might have any any
animal products in them so
vegans often try to find
foods at the grocery store
that that come from
natural products that are
not animal based and
so there there has to be a
symbol on the back of
the box or the jar that
says that it's vegan.
That's right so in that case
they don't drink milk
they don't eat eggs nothing
that you can think of
that comes from an animal
but on the other hand
this person used to be a
pescatarian so this is
another type of a person
that has a special diet
very much like a vegetarian.
A pescatarian is a
person who is a vegetarian
but who also eats fish and
so maybe I'm a pescatarian
because I don't consider
fish to be animals.
Okay so I don't eat lamb
I don't eat chicken but
I do eat fish I'm a
pescatarian. All right so
a vegetarian does not
eat fish or any type of
meat the same as a vegan
but a pescatarian does
eat maybe shrimp and
fish and any type of animal
from the sea okay and
well that brings us up to
our next word a
pescatarian will eat seafood.
Seafood is a word we use
to describe animals that come
from the sea so not
just fish also like you
said shrimp and lobster
you could even think of
really delicious food like a
seafood pasta or seafood salad.
Okay so you got
clams you have oysters
anything that comes from the
sea is considered seafood right.
That's right and our last word in language
takeaway is an adjective we heard at the
end of the dialogue our
character said it must be tough.
Okay now tough is an
interesting word because
in English it has a few
different meanings but
what was the meaning of the
word tough in today's dialogue?
In today's dialogue
when the person said
it must be tough it's
basically saying it must be
difficult it must be
difficult to be a vegetarian.
Right so it's a hard
situation you could also say
oh man this homework
is really tough that means
it's hard it's difficult.
All right great so we've
taken a look at a lot
of key words there what
when you take a break listen to our
dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
Hey Julian do you want to go grab some
to eat? Sure what do you feel like having?
I really feel like
having a big juicy steak.
Oh okay I don't eat meat
but that's fine I'm sure
wherever we're going they
will have other options right?
I didn't know you
were a vegetarian.
I'm not. I'm a vegan.
A what? A vegan.
I don't eat or use any
animal based products.
I don't wear leather, eat
eggs, drink milk or anything
that comes from an
animal. I used to be a
pescaterian before
which basically means you
don't eat meat but still
have fish and seafood.
Wow that's interesting
it must be tough.
It's a bit difficult to
find vegetarian friendly
restaurants sometimes
but since more and more
people are vegetarians
or vegans nowadays it's
getting a bit less difficult. All right now
we've prepared three phrases for you let's
take a look at those
now on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder. So it's a
very interesting and very
very common phrase at
the beginning of today's
dialogue that we use
all the time in English.
This is to grab something
to eat. The character
says hey Julie you want to
go grab something to eat.
So taking that as a
phrase we are inviting
someone to go eat
something. That's right so
I could say hey do you
want to go eat something or
I could say hey do you want
to go grab something to eat.
Okay and the verb
grab is to take or to
hold in your hand. So you
want to go grab something
to eat is basically
that. Right but don't be
confused because grabbing
normally means holding with
your hand but to grab
something to eat generally
just means hey would you like
to go eat something with me.
Okay and of course
we want to go grab
something to eat and
the guy says I really feel
like having a big juicy steak.
So we feel like having a steak.
This is very spoken English so
remember when you're
talking to your friends this
is okay but maybe if
you're writing something
it's not as good. But I
feel like a steak means
I want to eat a steak. It
doesn't mean you are a steak.
No I don't feel like a steak like like a
piece of meat but I do want to eat a piece
of like I do want to
eat a steak and so I feel
like having or I feel like
a steak these are both
acceptable in spoken
English. So you basically
feel like doing something or
you feel like eating something.
For example if
we're going to have
dinner you can say I feel
like having Italian food.
Yeah I don't feel like having Italian food
tonight. I feel like having Mexican food.
And I also feel like watching a movie.
Exactly so great ways of using feel like
and then a verb like
having or watching a movie.
Now getting back to
the vegetarian the vegan
aspect of our dialogue we saw that the girl
explained how she doesn't eat or use any
animal based products.
So this these three words
animal based products. So product is basically
anything that will be sold or bought.
Animal based is a way to describe
a product. So some products
have animal products in
them right. So for example
my shoes are an animal
based product because they
are leather and leather comes
from cows which are animals.
So you're basically
saying that they have
something from an
animal. They are made up of
something that comes from
an animal like leather shoes.
Exactly and it's not just
shoes it's also shampoo
or some of the foods
that you eat like in jars
and cans and so it's
important if you're a vegan
to look on the side of
the can or the side of the
box and see is this an
animal based product.
Are there animal products
in this? Right right okay.
A lot of interesting things
in this dialogue today.
Why don't we listen
to it one last time
and boy it back. Hey
Julian do you want to go
grab something to eat?
Sure what do you feel like
having? I really feel like
having a big juicy steak.
Oh okay I don't eat
meat but that's fine I'm
sure wherever we're going
they will have other options right.
I didn't know you
were a vegetarian.
I'm not. I'm a vegan. A what? A vegan. I
don't eat or use any animal based products.
I don't wear leather, eat eggs, drink milk
or anything that comes from an animal.
I used to be a pescatarian
before which basically
means you don't eat meat
but still have fish and seafood.
Wow that's interesting
it must be tough.
It's a bit difficult
to find vegetarian
friendly restaurants
sometimes but since more and
more people are vegetarians
or vegans nowadays
it's getting a bit less difficult. All
right so talking about vegan vegetarians,
pescatarians it seems
like these diets or these
lifestyles are more and
more popular but as we
saw in the dialogue it
can be a little bit difficult
especially in maybe in countries where
it's not so popular to to have these diets.
Definitely I think that in
places where you can find vegan
and vegetarian products
very easily, being a
vegetarian becomes much
more easy because you have
more options but if
you're living in a country
where it's very hard to
eat a meal without having
meat then you might just
eat potatoes every day and
it will get very very
difficult and very boring.
Well that's one of the
main arguments or the
main concerns with people
is that even though you
can argue that you
can get all the vitamins
or many of the vitamins
and minerals from nuts
and from vegetables it's still not healthy
to completely exclude from your diet maybe
sources like proteins like
meat or eggs or dairy products.
That's right and so in in America for example
it's very easy to find supplements you
can take vitamins like
calcium and you can have
pills that will give you
some protein and you
can find all sorts of
exotic vegetables that will
help you supplement
your diet but in a place like
trying to for example
I think it can be a lot
harder to find those
products and to find those
supplements and so
being a vegan especially or
a vegetarian poses a
lot more challenges.
Especially I think with what
you mentioned that products
are usually labeled
where they tell you if they
have any any animal based
products in there whereas
in other countries it's
probably not labeled and
it's a little even things
like getting the fat
free things are a little bit more difficult
in other countries like for example China.
That's right so we would
like to know are there
many vegans or vegetarians
in your country and if
there are do you think
it's hard for them to buy
food why or why not
let us know our website is
www.engospart.com.
Alright we'll see you guys there. Bye!